Hi, if you're like me, you spend hours scrolling on TikTok or Pinterest looking at Minecraft
building ideas without the intent to ever actually build them. Now, I don't know about you, but
sometimes inspiration just randomly hits. And I have to play Minecraft. Like, that's all that's
on my mind. And lately I've been seeing a whole lot of cottagecore Minecraft content circulating
around the internet, getting a lot of views, and so I downloaded some shaders and launched
Minecraft at like 6 FPS and built this for nostalgia. And if you're like literally any
person who's played Minecraft over the years, these houses were the bomb. They were like move-in
ready. Of course, there was only room for like three things to fit in there. And then there was
this problem. It's Minecraft cottagecore aesthetic because the mushroom houses with this aesthetic
are like next level. They are chef's kiss. They are immaculate. And suddenly your wikiHow tutorial
on how to make simple mushroom houses featuring acacia plank flooring are more aesthetic than
the 2013 mustache trend. And if this, uh, strangely specific scenario applies to you, then, um, boy will
you like this tutorial. So now I present three ways to make mushroom houses in Minecraft. Yay.
So the first house is pretty easy. Um, you're going to want to start out with a statistically
impossible mushroom in the middle of a field and use bone meal to make it big. Now stare
at that mushroom until you decide to mutilate it to look aesthetic like this. I wanted the
mushroom to look a bit different than the other simple mushroom houses you typically see,
so I went for a more of a bell-shaped curve for the top of the mushroom. You could also use one
of those mini water bottles for reference. I modeled mine based on an upside down flower pot
and I think it turned out pretty good. Once you have achieved maximum upside down flower pot
conformity, then you can start modifying the stem to make it look stockier. I used the mushroom stem
block and smooth quartz stairs, and if you're in survival you'll probably want to mine a few of the
big mushrooms with a silk touch axe to get the materials for this. I used birch plank flooring
to match the rest of the interior. Now I really like this house but there's not much room. Sorry
for my spore sense of humor. Here's the big grand reveal of this house. Very simple, I give it a 8
out of 10. Next house. This is a little bit more difficult than the last one and so you're going
to start out by making a frame that looks like the outline of a handmade cube of Play-Doh, the kind
that the edges never seem sharp enough, and then start sculpting it to look like the body of this
absurdly priced plastic Minnie Mouse teapot I found on Amazon. I use smooth quartz blocks, slabs,
and stairs to accomplish this, and if you want to use mushroom stem blocks I'm sure you could,
but I just like quartz because it makes the mushroom stem seem smooth and continuous, sort of
like a differentiable equation. Also because it's not a pain to get all those stems. After this,
start making the stem taller to look almost like a BB-8, and then give the wannabe BB-8 some
helicopter blades. These will be the radius of your circular mushroom cap. Then connect those
little helicopter blades to form a circle. Also, I never really found these graphs useful. I always
find them on like TikTok, but then again I always just wing it and it doesn't look very circular,
so maybe they're helpful to you, but mine turned out pretty great in the end. Anyway, start outlining
the circle in red mushroom blocks, and then be indecisive, and then decide on making the easy
way out, and make a circular spherical looking mushroom cap. Mine is about six blocks tall,
and unlike me, you probably want to make sure there's no weird blocks left exposed.
Then I made the door and the window and outlined them in the most superior wood type,
spruce wood. I used planks, fences, and stairs, as well as oak leaves for the window boxes. To add
some extra whimsy, you can make a dilapidated cobblestone chimney and drape that with oak leaves.
To add some stuff to the interior, I connected the chimney to a fireplace furnace type thing,
and then added an unnecessary amount of bookshelves and leaves, because when in doubt,
add oak leaves and bookshelves. That's my motto. Also, I used flower pots, turtle eggs,
and sea pickles for the inside, and then I discovered that in 1.16.5, you can place
turtle eggs on flower pots, which is kind of weird. Anyway, I used vines as a ladder to the
attic area, which will be a cute little bedroom. I outlined the roof with spruce wood, and then
placed some bookshelves behind them. This would also be a cool enchanting room, but the house
demands a bedroom, so I added in a skylight, which looks good with the shaders, and I'm sure
it would look good without them. So, this is the finished build. It only took me about 45 minutes
to do in creative, so not too bad. Ta-da! Alright, on to the last one. This one is kind of hard,
but not like PryorGaming at the end of his TikToks kind of hard. You're going to want to start out with
a circular base like such, and then add a small circle attached to it. Once you have your two
little circle buddies, start making them taller and rounder. I focused on the bigger circle first,
because it's going to be the centerpiece for the build. Also, if this video gets 100 likes,
I'll make a video of my little sister following this tutorial to see how she does, because she's
bad at building and I'm bad at explaining things. Okay, back to the tutorial. If you don't know
what shape to make the base of the big mushroom, I refer to the gourd from the 2007 Disney
classic, Secret of the Magic Gourd, and mine turned out pretty alright. Also, I need to know,
was anyone else low-key traumatized by that movie? Because when I first saw that movie, I guess I
just thought gourds were strange pumpkins, so for the longest time, I was fundamentally confused on
what gourds were. So anyway, you're going to start making another one of those helicopter circle
things, and here's, here's a better explanation using calculus if you want to know how to make circles
in Minecraft. Presenting! Building circles! Yay! So you're going to want to start out with this sort of
graph paper, just trace something circular onto it, and then fill in the blocks that the circle
crosses. Make sure it all has the same radius, and then this is where the calculus comes in. If you
look at tangent lines, you know what tangent lines are, I hope. You probably don't, um, but the slope
of the tangent line is sort of the slope of if you were to draw the slope through the, like, the grid
squares of the circle. This made a lot more sense inside my head, but you can trace pretty much any
circle onto graph paper and repeat this process. Just make sure the radius is the same and that
each quadrant is the same, and there you go, you have a circle in Minecraft. Okay, now moving on to
our other little mushroom buddy, you're going to want to make him a wonky little mushroom that sort of
stems off from the big one. It's really hard to explain how I did this, but I would recommend
using organic shapes and have the top of the mushroom thinner than the base. Then add a tiny
little cap. For the top of the big mushroom, I basically did the same thing as I did for the
medium tutorial, and despite it being vastly bigger, the cap is about the same height, maybe
even five blocks this time. I kind of wanted to make it sort of squishy like the first build,
but I lost all my brain cells thinking about calculus. If you want the mushroom to be super
cottagecore, you can add some birch leaves that hang like vines and some hanging lanterns. You
could also use shroomlights. I also added a dilapidated chimney to match the vibe.
And then for the interior, I started again by connecting the fireplace to the chimney and built
a loft area with a ladder leading up to it. And then I got distracted by a wandering trader and
quickly resumed my work, and I used an absurd amount of birch leaves to decorate. If you can't
tell from my Pinterest page, birch leaves are my favorite. Also, if you're wondering how they move
in the wind, that's the shaders, and I use BSL shaders. As far as I know, they only work for
Java Edition. I made a little kitchen space in front of one of the windows, complete with some
cake and some turtle eggs, and then added some seating by the fire. In front of the other window,
I made what HGTV calls a breakfast nook, complete with some plants. While the bedroom space is
smaller than the previous build, I think it turned out nicely and I wouldn't mind living there.
After decorating the bedroom, I remembered there was a bunch of empty space in the loft,
which I promptly decorated with barrels because that can be practical when they're not converting
all the villagers to fishers, and I did notice I accidentally made a sort of shrine to Pinocchio,
which is cool I guess. On the outside, I was going for a house-ish entrance, but I ended up
making it more like a hobbit hole with spruce trapdoors and slabs and stairs. I also added some
dark oak for better contrast, and ended up expanding the windows downward because it just
looked better. I added some shutters to the bedroom window and shroom lights to better illuminate it
at night. There was something that was still missing though, and I couldn't decide what to do,
so I tried this thing I saw on TikTok where you make mushrooms out of end rods and mushroom blocks,
which I was a bit skeptical of, but I really liked how they turned out. So yeah, those are
three mushroom houses you could easily build in Minecraft. Comment below which one you'd live in,
I know I definitely would pick the second one because of the skylight, but that's just me.
And if you enjoy this content and would like to see more dollar store Grian tutorials,
please feel free to hit subscribe. See y'all later, bye!